This is your brain thinking and this is
your brain using AI. In 2025, they did a
study where they had people write essays
while relying on tragic. They took 54
people that were separated into three
groups and they asked them to write
several essays while researchers used an
EEG to look at their brain activity. The
group that used CHABT had the lowest
brain activation among all groups. The
people who used Chachi PT could barely
even remember the things that they wrote
about in their essays. And when they had
that same Chad PT group write another
essay without using any tools, their
levels of brain activity was even lower
than normal. So the trap that a lot of
people fall into when they use AI tools
is that you think you're activating
critical thinking, but you're actually
not. AI use by itself is not going to
make you dumb. It's how you use it. If
you use it passively, it's going to make
you lazy and not think for yourself. But
if you use it actively, it can be an
amazing tool.